<!-- doc/src/feedback.xml -->

<chapter id="feedback">
  <title>Feedback and Getting Involved</title>
  <section>
    <title>Bug Reporting and Other Feedback</title>
    <para>
      The <application>skit</application> developers welcome feedback.
      If you like skit, if you don&apos;t, if you want new features, if
      the documentation sucks, if you've found a bug, or if you'd like
      to get involved, we'd like to hear from you.  Email us at
      <email>skit-general@lists.pgfoundry.org</email>.
    </para>
    <para>
      If <application>skit</application> fails to do what it claims,
      that is a bug.  If it does something unexpected, and you don't
      like it, that may also be a bug.  If it generates ugly or
      poor-performing <acronym>DDL</acronym> that may be a bug.
    </para>
    <para>
      If you find a bug, we want to hear from you.
    </para>
    <section>
      <title>How to file a bug report</title>
      <para>
	By email to <email>skit-general@lists.pgfoundry.org </email>.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section>
      <title>What to include in a bug report</title>
      <para>
	If we can reproduce your problem, you are much more likely to
	get a fix in a reasonable time.  So the more information you
	provide, the better.  Please give us:
	<itemizedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      the skit version;
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      a short description of the problem;
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      the RDBMS version;
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	     instructions for reproducing the problem;
	    </para>
	    <para>
	      Copies of the source xml files, or a pg_dump, without
	      data, of the source database would be very useful, though
	      if these are large files, it would be better to offer them
	      and wait for a response from the developers.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      any clues	you can provide based on your attempts to get
	      around the issue.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Getting Involved in the Development of Skit</title>
    <para>
      If you would like to be involved in the development of skit, we
      would like to hear from you at
      <email>skit-general@lists.pgfoundry.org</email>.
    </para>
    <para>
      If you wish to contact the author offlist, you can find him at his
      website, <ulink url="http://bloodnok.com/Marc.Munro">bloodnok.com</ulink>.
    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
