<!-- doc/src/roadmap.xml -->

<chapter id="roadmap">
  <title>The Development Road Map</title>
  <para>
    This section needs to be fleshed-out, but here is a list of things
    that need to be done:
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  improved documentation;
	</para>
	<para>
	  Particularly this, the developer&apos;s guide.  Also
	  documentation in other formats.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  grouping tsort for generate;
	</para>
	<para>
	  We want to add a different, optional, tsort algorithm that
	  orders its results so that related items are as close as
	  possible to each other.  This would mean that all tables in one
	  schema would be generated before the tables in another, and
	  that all cluster objects (roles, tablespaces) would be dealt
	  with before dealing with non-schema objects.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  grep command;
	</para>
	<para>
	  A regular expression-based filter to allow subsets of an
	  <acronym>XML</acronym> stream to be selected and processed
	  independently of the rest of the stream.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  support for metadata;
	</para>
	<para>
	  Databases are rarely defined entirely by their schema.
	  Usually meta-data is also part of a database design.  Skit
	  should support this.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  support for data impacted by schema changes;
	</para>
	<para>
	  Better support is required for handling the impacts on
	  existing database data of schema changes.  This is tricky and
	  is a big area.  If you have ideas or use cases, the skit
	  developers would love to hear from you.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  improved code comments and doxygen;
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  optimise the generated <acronym>DDL</acronym>;
	</para>
	<para>
	  There are occasions when unecessary temporary grants are
	  issued, and for drops, skit issues explicit, redundant drops
	  for the descendant objects of objects being dropped (eg grants
	  on tables are revoked before dropping the table even though
	  this is superfluous.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  shout option for generate;
	</para>
	<para>
	  This would create <acronym>DDL</acronym> in upper case.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  allow upgrades of extensions to be done by directly modifying
	  the objects within the extension;
	</para>
	<para>
	  This might be useful, or it might not.  It won't be a priority
	  unless someone asks for it.
	</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
	<para>
	  improved performance.
	</para>
	<para>
	  Some operations are way slower than they should be.
	</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>
  <para>
    This is not in any particular order.  If there is something you
    want, then lobby for it or, better still, offer to help.
  </para>
</chapter>
